[portal powering up]
Come on, we gotta--
Whoa!
[zombie-like moaning]
Fritz and Spitz?
Oh, no!
They're hollow!
Those spectral jerk-faces
attacked the Monastery!
No one attacked the Monastery,
Wyldfyre.
But can't say the same
for the Land of Lost Things.
Do you know
what happened to them?
Yeah,
the same thing is happening
all over the place.
[Riyu yelping]
[Sora laughing]
Aw, I missed you too, Riyu.
[grumbling affectionately]
I know, I'm sorry I left,
but I had to make sure
Arin was okay.
[grumbling curiously]
And he'll be back
to see you too.
[grumbling joyfully]
So people are
getting drained like this
outside of
the Land of Lost Things?
It's ThunderFang...
using the Forbidden Five
to collect souls,
trying to become
a Source Dragon.
Tell me there's a plan.
The Ninja always have a plan.
We do,
but it's wild.
[zombie-like groaning]
[spectral shrieking]
[roaring]
[ThunderFang cackling]
[evil laughter]
[Lloyd] So we take
that thing to the well
where ThunderFang's energy's
coming from,
and once the other teams
wake up their halves
of the Arc Dragon of Focus,
it'll be summoned
right to our spot.
Piece of cake! Day saved.
Uh, night saved.
"Piece of cake"? Really?
That's even optimistic for me.
Trying to get psyched up.
Yes, this will be hard,
but if we start thinking
it's impossible,
we don't stand a chance.
Uh, you take this thing.
I'm gonna mess it up.
Why would you mess it up?
[sighing] Come on,
messing things up
is what I do best.
It's basically
my elemental power.
You think I started out
with skills?
Uh, yeah.
You're the Legendary
Green Ninja.
You didn't know me as a kid.
There were
plenty of reasons to think
I'd never be a Ninja,
but confidence
is just another skill to build.
Someday,
you're going to be
one of the greatest Ninja
to ever live.
No, I'm not.
Lloyd, I finally have
my parents,
and the Land of Lee is filled
with other kids' parents,
other peoples' loved ones.
I came here with you
to release their souls
from ThunderFang,
to help reunite families
like mine,
but when this is all over...
I'm quitting the Ninja.
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[grunting with impact]
[exhaling]
What the--?
[sighing]
Weird.
Well, that's Mysterium for ya.
Hmm.
All right,
as long as Bleckt's directions
to the cave are accurate,
I got this.
Yup, I got this.
Don't need anyone else.
Definitely not Jay.
[chuckling]
I mean, forget about me and him,
what about being a Ninja?
How is being a mercenary
who cares only about money
more exciting?
Hello?
Ninja!
You're talking
to yourself again, Nya.
[sighing] Anyway...
Cave of Tones!
[pounding against door]
I'm sure that's just Mysterium
being weird and Mysterium-y.
[pounding continuing]
[moaning] Janet...
Sorceress?
[groaning] Janet... Janet...
Oh, no. Not you too.
-[thudding]
-Whoa!
[grunting] Oof!
What?
[gasping]
[Sorceress muttering]
Here's the deal, Riyu.
We gotta get to Djinjago, fast,
but we don't know where it is.
The only times
we've been there,
we were summoned,
or Zanth flew us...
[Riyu grumbling eagerly]
Looks like you're thinking
what we're thinking.
Zanth!
And Rontu?
I've been helping this one
with his Ninja training.
He has shown much potential.
[grumbling modestly]
I anticipate
his first Spinjitzu Tornado
will be soon,
if he keeps up his hard work.
I just achieved
my first tornado too,
like, yesterday!
You can do it, buddy!
We can do it.
[Riyu grumbling in agreement]
Zanth,
you took us to Djinjago before.
Can you do it again?
[Zanth roaring]
She says she feels
her homeland regrowing,
and would love to see
what it's become.
Whoo! Let's go!
Dibs on the front seat!
Riyu, you should stay
and focus on your training.
[grumbling]
True, little one.
Not much point in training
if you don't save the world now.
You have always been
a wise little dragon.
Go, but please be careful.
[grumbling in agreement]
[Sorceress groaning
and muttering]
Sorceress, watch out!
[blades clashing]
[zombie-like moaning]
[grunting with effort]
H'yah! Yaah!
What is this thing?
[grunting with effort]
Had enough?
[gasping]
H'yah! H'ah! H'ah!
Knock it off!
Or I will!
[Sorceress moaning]
What the--?
Put me down, you oaf!
Sorceress?
Do I know you?
I'm Nya.
We met after
the Battle of the Blood Moon.
You helped us save
the Cloud Kingdom, remember?
Blood Moon?
Cloud Kingdom?
You're just doing words,
trying to confuse
a kindly old coconut.
Are you the Sorceress
or a coconut?
Eh, a little bit of column A,
a little of column B,
you know how it is.
I'm a magical back-up copy
of the Sorceress's personality.
The non-coconut Sorceress
made me a bunch of years ago,
in case Janet's whole
mind-wipe scheme ever worked.
[Sorceress muttering]
Janet... Janet...
I just got activated,
probably because that one's
pfft! right now.
No offense!
Janet...
[splashing]
Okay...
but why a coconut?
Good melons were out of season.
So, what's your deal?
Did we, uh...
did you and the
non-coconut Sorceress
have plans?
Ladies' weekend? Staycation?
[sighing]
Long story short,
I need to go to a place
called the Cave of Tones.
Fast.
Ever heard of it?
Yeah, I'm not tone deaf.
Pfft!
Even as a coconut,
I've still got it!
Uh...
"West past Mt. Mollin"?
Yowza!
Those directions are outdated.
[groaning] Bleckt!
Yeah, that mountain
isn't there anymore.
Earthquake.
Now it's just
a vast chasm of doom.
Where are you getting
your travel info,
an ancient vault?
Actually, yes.
Huh! Then it's a good thing
I'm going with you!
I will show you
a current route,
one that won't get you killed.
Maimed, maybe, but not killed...
probably. Let's go!
Janet... Janet...
[zombie-like moaning]
[gasping]
Oh no!
Not you too, Cole!
He fought hard to free
the Finders' souls, but...
Come on.
I've got you.
Wyldfyre!
-Flame fist!
And look who I brought.
Sora?
Hey. I'm back.
Sora, I couldn't sleep,
I was so worried about you.
You were?
Well, I mean...
we all were, not just me.
I'm sure others couldn't sleep--
Where's Arin?
Uh, with Lloyd.
Look, as you probably
know already,
the Merged Realms
have a big problem,
and we need to help.
What do we have to do?
[distant thunder rumbling]
[panting]
...and after the Merge,
all us Ninja
ended up in different places.
Did you find each other?
Yeah, but...
I'm not sure
that was a good thing.
Ooh, this sounds juicy,
and I would know.
I'm a coconut.
Go on.
[gasping]
Oh.
Well, this shouldn't be here.
Then why is it here?
You led me to a dead end!
Magical lands sometimes change
for no reason.
How am I supposed to know?
I'm a backup coconut!
[gasping]
Can I cross on those?
Yes... and no.
The Mercurial Mushrooms
aren't always the most stable.
It's the only option we have.
Uh... so you were saying
getting the Ninja back together
wasn't a good thing?
Yeah.
Jay... I...
We were together, before,
but when I found him,
he lost his memory...
[grunting with effort]
...and he was a totally
different person.
I thought if we could
just spend time together,
he'd remember, but...
Hup! ...it didn't work.
How can people change like that?
H'yah! Whoa!
[grunting with effort]
Oh, people change, sister.
I had someone close,
a BFF.
We did everything together,
studied, traveled,
sang in the same
a capella group.
I was the beatboxer!
♪ Boots, cats, cats and boots ♪
♪ Boots and cats
Cats and boots ♪
But...
over time,
our priorities changed.
I was still focused
on the magic, the people,
friendships,
but all he cared about
was more and more wealth.
I imagine he was another
magic-wielder like you, right?
Hup! Someone you could
share everything with?
Yeah... something like that.
[gasping] Whoa!
[panting]
[grunting with effort]
[yelping] Oh!
I don't see how we're both
making it out of this.
Let me go!
I'm just a coconut copy.
No way!
Ninja have this whole thing
about not quitting.
[grunting with effort]
H'yah!
Ah... h'yah!
Phew! [panting]
Let's hope there are
no more surprises like that.
This is Mysterium.
Nothing but surprises.
[grumble talking]
[Wyldfyre] Whee!
Are we there yet?
How far away is this place?
Frak, Zanth is doing her best.
We'll get to Djinjago
when we get to Djinjago!
But time is, like,
of the essence.
Then let's sing
to pass the time!
♪ Oh... what do you do
with a sleepy Ninja? ♪
♪ What do you do with
a sleepy Ninja? ♪
♪ What do you-- ♪
Why don't we practice
the melody Bleckt taught us?
We're gonna need to play it
on the bells
to awaken
our half of the Arc Dragon.
[singing melody]
[Frak harmonizing]
[singing]
Please don't harmonize.
We've got to remember
the primary notes,
and that just makes it harder.
Sorry, I just habitually
harmonize in thirds.
Years of vocal training.
[rolling lips] Brrr... ah!
Okay, I'm warm.
From the one, please?
[singing melody in unison]
[♪♪♪]
[singing loudly and out of tune]
[grumbling in protest]
[singing loudly]
[gasping]
Let's add words for funzies!
I've been super into
sea shanties lately.
♪ Yo-ho, the ocean calls! ♪
♪ The Ninja kicks
and the bad guys fall! ♪
We cannot let her
ring the bells.
[Wyldfyre] I heard that!
Not my fault you can't
appreciate a good shanty.
Let's play the Quiet Game.
One, two, three, go!
[groaning]
Who wants snacks?
I mean, I didn't bring
any snacks.
Why would I say that?
[rummaging]
[munching]
Okay, but seriously,
are we there yet?
Time is of the essence.
Zanth, my friend,
can you sense Djinjago?
Are we getting closer?
[growling]
[Frak] Was that a yes?
[all] Whoa!
[grumbling]
[gasping]
Are you okay, girl?
Wha-hoo!
I don't even know
what's happening,
but this is awesome!
[all yelping]
Zanth, what is going on here?
Whoa!
[roaring]
[grunting with impact]
[gasping]
Whoa!
Does she normally
do stuff like this?
She got really big once before,
but it wasn't like this.
Zanth, quite a glow-up,
but what brought this on
right-- aah!
[grumbling wearily]
[all yelping] Ah!
No, no, no!
[groaning]
Djinjago!
We made it!
[♪♪♪]
[ThunderFang roaring]
Someone is nearing
the Arc Dragon of Focus.
The Ninja...
They dare attempt to awaken
my eternal enemy?
[grumbling]
Whoa...
I had no idea
Djinjago would've
grown this much so fast,
and it looks like Arrakore
moved it over the water.
[groaning]
[kissing]
Look at all this!
New towers, and fountains?
Is that a Monastery
portal gate?
So much has changed,
and it's all so majestic.
-[yelping]
-Glad you like it!
Arrakore!
Sora!
Riyu!
[grumbling happily]
Oh, I do love when you visit!
So good to see you again!
[grumbling happily]
And you brought friends!
Zanth, is that you?
[growling]
Look at you!
I knew my work
expanding Djinjago
would have amazing results,
but I never expected
it would infuse
a Djinjagan dragon
with such energy!
There it is, Freebooters.
Djinjago.
Rapton never doesn't find
what he wants.
Shouldn't it be
"Rapton always finds
what he wants?"
[Rapton] What's that?!
Is someone questionalating
Rapton's grammaticalism
masteritude?
No, of course not.
[snarling]
[sighing wearily]
We're here!
Wow...
but we need a Cave of Tones.
It's behind the water!
Let's go!
We just need to play the tones
in the order this Blecky--
Bleckt.
Bleckt? Really?
Sounds like someone barfing.
His parents didn't do him
any favors with that name.
Anyhoosy, we do
what he told you,
then badda-bing, we awaken
the half Arc Dragon of Focus
and save the world! Na-na!
Only if the other Ninja
pull off their parts too.
Oh, you don't think they will?
They've never
let me down before.
Ah, sounds like you've got
a pretty good group of friends
behind you.
Now, come on, let's do this!
[heavy footsteps]
[gasping] Oh, no...
Great.
More Mysterium surprises?
Who disturbs Powerlid,
the ultimate cyclops,
also known as the ultimate
object of admiration?
Ugh... pretend I'm not here.
Hide me in a tree,
I'm just your regular
run-of-the-mill coconut.
Do you know that cyclops?
No!
Yes! I do. I did.
Yeah, but I never thought
I'd run into him again.
Wait, is this...?
The former BFF
I was talking about? Yes!
And it looks like
becoming a greedy guts
didn't amount to much
if he lives in a cave.
Serves him right.
Ugh, another one
of you Ninjerks
here to steal Powerlid's stuff!
Time to grind your bones
into powder
like Powerlid does best!
[growling]
Here you go.
Some aged spore-rot broth.
Auntie Croakwart's old recipe,
yum, yum, yum!
[gagging and groaning]
I'll be honest,
the flavor's, uh,
a little bit on the sharp side.
[sniffing]
[coughing]
[fly buzzing]
Are you sure
that's even safe to eat?
It smells rank...
and I live
in a wasteland of junk.
It's very nourishing
and healing...
if you can keep it down.
Well, if nothing else,
maybe the... smell
will revive them.
Don't worry,
I've got plenty left.
[fly buzzing]
Oh.
Does she not eat?
No, she eats all the time.
Well, how does...?
Um...
I mean, where does the food...?
[stammering]
Of all the questions
I need answers to right now,
that's very far down the list.
Cole? Can you hear me?
It's Geo.
[moaning]
What can I do?
Can you...
blink twice
if you can understand me?
[moaning]
[portal powering up]
Who's coming now?
If the Ninja are back
this fast,
it probably means
something went wrong.
No, no!
Well, he can't be here!
How can he be here?!
Don't get any closer!
The Ninja are scattered
across the Merged Lands.
Save yourself
the pain and suffering.
Submit.
You can't intimidate us.
Ninja never quit.
You are not Ninja.
We're... Ninja-adjacent,
and Ninja-adjacent
never quit either.
So be it.
Eat this!
[gagging]
[spluttering]
[screaming in rage]
[groaning fearfully]
[tapping button]
[roaring]
[♪♪♪]